Ching-Cheong Lee

9121-8040

github.com/machingclee

machingclee@gmail.com

Personal Statement_

I graduated from HKUST with an M.Phil degree in Mathematics, worked in both academic and nonacademic fields, and with solid knowledge in front end programming. I am also confident in both software development and AI models development for solving problems in diversified scenarios.

Personal and Portfolio Homepage

I keep sharing my blog post as a record of what I have learnt. I also list some of my side projects there:

https://machingclee.github.io/blog

Experience_

Software Engineer *Wonderbricks Limited* mid-May 2023 - Present

Hong Kong

- Build, revamp and maintain React projects in Typescript.
- Build Realtime Chat Application in Mobile by using React-Native in Typescript; Create custom interactive UI component using react-native-reanimated.
- Maintain Springboot project, build APIs using both MySQL and Mongodb.
- Migrate part of the services from java backend to Serverless Lambda Functions in Python.

Al Engineer mid-Aug 2022 - 04/2023

Eye Catching Limited

Hong Kong

- Help maintain angular project.
- Study eye-tracing related algorithm.
- Study and deploy machine leanning algorihtm in web-app and desktop-app.

Senior Software Developer

09/2021 - mid-Aug 2022

RaSpect Intelligence Inspection Limited

Hong Kong

- Maintain React Next project.
- Data scrapping of house transaction records, automation on tracking latest rtk-data on geodetics website.
- Al Related. Implemented the following using PyTorch.
 - 1. **Text Detection and Removal.** In order to perform defect classification on signboard, I am responsible to create models for text detection and text removal to remove possible noise that interfere our defect classifier.
 - 2. Crack and Rust Detection. Both using faster rcnn.
 - 3. **DefectGAN.** Successfully implemented a DefectGAN (no source code available yet in paperswithcode) that creates crack, spalling, etc synthetic data for defect detection.
 - 4. Model Integration with Backend. Exposed clean enough API for software integration.

Software Engineer

09/2020 - mid-08/2021

EAB Systems (Hong Kong) Limited

Hong Kong

- Frontend Related. Build video conferencing frontend and backend application in React, Twilio.js and express.js. Build CMS system that lets users create their own single page application.
- **Deep Learning Related.** Build CSV Importer (together with an express layer, a Flask layer and a tensorflow-serving layer) that can parse a csv/excel file and perform:
 - 1. **Data Classsification.** Classify column based on existing data using LSTM model with two dense layers and finally a softmax.
 - 2. **Auto Date-reformatting.** Based on machine learning model (transformer) that can translate all common form of date into YYYY-MM-DD format.

Data Classification and Auto Date-refomatting are separately two models placed inside tensorflow-serving for deployment.

09/2019 - 08/2020

eLearningPro Hong Kong

• Create HTML5 Coursewares, maintaining web pages and constructing frontend application using React.

Senior Research Assistant

03/2015 - 10/2015

Department of Mathematics, Hong Kong Baptist University

Hong Kong

Study HJB equations arised in a specific financial games

Research Assistant 09/2014 - 02/2015

Department of Mathematics, Hong Kong University of Science and Technology

Hong Kong

• Study the property of viscosity solution of HJB equations

Education_

MicroMaster in A.I. and Programming

03/2019 - 06/2019

Tecky Academy, Hong Kong

M.Phil. in Mathematics

09/2012 - 08/2014

The Hong Kong University of Science and Technology, Hong Kong

B.Sc. in Mathematics (First Class Honor)

09/2009 - 06/2012

The Hong Kong University of Science and Technology, Hong Kong.

Skills_

Source Control

Git

Deployment

• Docker • Basic CI/CD Pipeline in Gitlab

Cloud (AWS)

• Security Group • Target Group • ECS with EC2 or Fargate • Route53 • Load Balancer

• S3 • CloudFront • Lambda Functions

Java

Springboot
Hibernate
MyBatis

C#

Windows Presentation Foundation

C++

CMake Ecosystem
Libtorch
OpenCV
ImGui for Desktop App

Python

Tensorflow v2
PyTorch
Pandas
Flask
ONNX
Openpyxl
Boto3

Typescript

• React • React-Native • Redux • Redux-Saga • Next.js • Electron.js

• Electron with Next.js • Node.js • Express.js • Socket.io • Twilio.js • Knex.js

Mongoose.js

Deep-Learning

• Embed custom trained pytorch model in ONNX format into frontend

Implementation from scratch and training experience with CNN such as

Object Detection

• Text Detection with Rotation

Image Classification

Image Generation and Image In-painting

• Implementation and training experience with LSTM Model and Transformer to do:

· Summarization on a column of data

• Translation of random date format into standard YYYY-MM-DD one